Gulliver's Travels (1939)
Based on Jonathan Swift's
Immortal Tale
Produced by Max Fleischer
Directed by Dave Fleischer
I, Lemuel Gulliver
give thee a faithful history
of my most interesting adventure
in the South Sea.
On the 5th day of November, 1699,
having reached latitude 30 degrees,
two minutes south,
a storm of great fury suddenly...
All's well!
# All's well! What's a rainy day? #
# Never mind that cloud. #
# Behind that cloud you'll find a golden ray. #
# All's well! Laugh your fears away. #
# See the light ahead. Right ahead. #
# There's a moonlit night ahead. #
# Everyone, come on have fun. All's well! #
Why do they make me sing that song?
The poet who wrote it was certainly wrong.
It's bright ahead. The light's ahead.
I'd rather go home and go right to bed.
All's well!
My feet are wet and my bunions ache,
and yet I've to keep wide awake,
all night!
I wake folks up to tell them
things are all right!
And, # All's well! What's a rainy day? #
# Never mind that cloud. #
# Behind that cloud you'll find a golden ray. #
# All's well! Laugh your fears away. #
# See the light ahead. Right ahead. #
# There's a moonlit night ahead. #
# Everyone, come on have fun. All...
A, A, All's well! Wha, wha, what's a rainy day?
The king has visitors.
Do you know they're signing a wedding contract?
There's a giant on the beach!
There, there's a giant out there!
Your majesty.
Thank you, your majesty.
Marriage Contract
King Little of Lilliput
Does this 5th day of November 1699
give the hand of his daughter
Princess Glory
to Prince David
son of Bombo
King of Blefuscu!
Quite in order, fine.
King Bombo!
Well we did it, you little rascal, you.
We did it.
Yes we, we certainly did, didn't we?
Just a couple of old dag cupids, I think! [laughs}
Your majesty, the wedding things are here.
There's a giant on the beach!
Let me go!
Let me go! Let me go!
There's a giant on the beach! Let me go!
Exquisite taste, exquisite!
Roses, Freesia, Rhododendrons,
Ranunculus, Snap Dragons, and Daisies.
Ahh!
They're pretty Posies, aren't they?
Beautiful blooms, beautiful!
Oh!
May I?
Oh, please do!
Magnificent!
Oh! A masterpiece!
Vanilla. Wow!
# Faithful. Remember, that whatever I do,
I'm always faithful, my love. #
# Faithful, with all my soul and thankful for you, #
# who came from heaven above. #
# We'll dance tonight together,
on a world with me we'll find. #
My only little daughter. I dread losing her.
Huh, Buck up there old boy, you're not
losing a daughter. You’re gaining a son.
My son!
# So I'll be faithful and faithful as I promise to be,
and you'll be for all mine. #
Hmm. Lovely melody.
Yes, we like it.
That is Faithful. The song of Lilliput.
It will be played at the wedding tomorrow.
Of course. Of course.
What's that, Faithful? Oh, no, no! Forever!
The song of Blefuscu must be
played at the wedding.
But Bombo, Faithful is always
played at our weddings.
It, it's tradition, sir. And it's very pretty.
Yes, yes, I know. Pleasant little ditty,
oh but hardly appropriate for this great occasion.
But Forever! There's a song for you! Ha, ha!
Faithful will be played.
Bah! Fodder. Absolute fodder. It must be Forever!
Faithful.
Forever!
It will be Forever, or there will be no wedding!
No wedding? But the cake
and the pretty flowers and..
oh Bombo, you'll love Faithful.
Ahh!
It's war!
There's a giant on the beach!
War. Woe is me. Woe is me.
I found a mountain, your majesty. I found it!
It was man, a man mountain!
War isn't nice.
It was, was this big!
No, no. It was this big!
People get hurt in wars.
He's as big, as big as, as,.. big as, as, as..
Wait your majesty!
Bombo can't frighten me. No sir.
Don't stand there like a nincompoop!
I'm trying to tell you that there's a giant!
When I get my dandruff up, then look out.
But Glory, poor little Glory.
Don't look now gentleman, but it's war.
War? Whoopee!
# Forever, forever, #
# There won't be anyone but you. #
# Remember I'm true, my sweet. #
# Forever, forever, #
# You'll share in everything I do, #
# And keep smiling through, my sweet. #
# I'll have just you here in my heart, #
# And I'll trust you though we're apart. #
# So, forever, forever, #
# My guiding angel you will be. #
# So always have faith in me. #
Shh!
War. Ha. Ha. Rolls off my back like a duck.
But, but I'm, but I'm trying to tell ya!
I'm telling ya there's, there's a...
What's on your mind?
I said..
Speak up, man.
There's a giant on the beach!
For heaven's sake, Gabby.
Button your mouth.
Can't you see I have a war on my hands?
Be off with you. Shoo! Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
A war?
Do you suppose he could be a, a spy?
Who's a spy? Who's a spy?
THE GIANT ON THE BEACH!
A giant? Giant? Why don't you tell me things?
Do something. Don't stand there.
Go. Sic the dogs on him.
Fetch him to me at once!
Wake up! Wake up!
There's a giant on the beach!
A giant on the beach!
Wake up, I tell ya! Wake up!
There's a giant on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up!
Giant on the beach!
There's a giant on the beach!
A giant on the beach!
Wake up, I tell ya! Wake up!
There's a giant on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up!
Giant on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up! There's a giant on the beach!
A giant on the beach!
Wake up! Wake up!
There's a giant on the beach!
A giant, on the beach?
A giant?
On the beach?
T-T-There's a, there's a, there's, there's a...
Giant on the beach!
Giant!
It's open!
A giant?
A giant on the beach!
Giant!
On the beach!
I said, "There's a giant on the beach!"
Bring cables and tools.
Bring horses and mules.
Bring snippers and clippers,
ladders and spools.
Bring Derek the rig,
and bring Floyd the jig.
Bring whatchamacallit. Little and big.
A thingamathud. A thingamajig.
And all kinds of things
and stuff like that there.
Follow me!
Shh!
Hmm!
Shh! Quiet. We're almost there.
Whoaa!
Wh, where, where is it?
I don't know, but it was right here.
Here?
Oh yeah? Well where is it now?
Well ah, ah, I can't understand it.
It was right here.
Honest.
Giant, huh! Dragging us out
into the dead of the night.
Yeah, chasing wild geese.
Gabby must have been seeing things.
Maybe it just got up and flew away.
Yeah, and breathing fire.
Look out Gabby.
Your giant's gonna bite ya!
Hey, hey fellas, maybe it was me he saw.
Look. I'm a giant! I'm a giant!
Psst!
Psst! Psst! Psst!
Listen.
I-I... t-t-told ya that there was
a-a-a gia, a giant on the b-b-beach.
And well, there he is.
Huh?
HE SAID, "THAT'S THE GIANT ON THE BEACH!"
Shh!
There isn't a moment to waste.
Every last man must do all that he can.
Work with the greatest of haste.
So bind up its hands, its arms,
its chest, its neck, its feet!
And I'll do the rest.
Let's go!
Quiet.
Hey?
Shh!
Careful!
Up!
Put him there! No! No! Here!
Don't be afraid man!
Aw! Aw! He got me! He got me!
Aw! Aw! Help! He's killing me!
I don't want to die! Help! Help!
He's killing me! Help!
Hey!
Well, what are you rubes waiting for?
Tie him up!
Get the wheel. Come on, roll in the plate.
Bring pegs to hold him.
Bring jacks, tacks, cleats, axe.
All kinds of things and stuff like that there!
Come on now! Let's go! Heave, ho!
Up! Up men! Up! Up!
Back up Billy!
Come on, Nicky.
Steady there, Bessie!
Back up, Billy!
Hip! Hip!
Ho!
...five, and six, and seven,
and eight, and nine, and oh!
Ready there below? Let's go!
Giddy up, Susie! Giddy up!
Lower wave in!
Careful! Careful!
All set below!
Okay, let's go!
Giddy up! Tally ho!
Giddy up!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Pull in the ropes there!
Not so fast! Not so fast!
Hurry up, there! Slow down!
Get the wheels past!
Phew! I don't know what they would do
around here without ME!
Ohhhh!
Heave! Heave!
Faithful was always played
at our weddings... Faithful.
Faithful.
Your, your, your majesty.
Huh?
I've got the giant!
The giant. Oh, yes, yes, the giant.
Well bring him in. Bring him in.
Okay. Okay.
Your majesty, I don't think he'd fit in here.
Oh you don't, huh?
So it's not good enough for him, hmm?
Well where is he?
Out there, your majesty.
Now, then.
Humph! Not good enough for him!
Well, where is he?
From here. On!
Call out the guards, the army, the navy,
women and children first, I'll see you later.
Search him, men. He may be armed.
Ohhhh!
Ugh! Why do I get out held?
Your majesty! Let me in!
Look your majesty! Let me in!
Let me in! Let me in!
Help! I don't like this!
Ohhhh!
Let me go! Help! Help!
Let me go! I don't wanna die!
Well, well. what have we got here?
Help! Help!
Don't eat me! Don't eat me!
Help! I won't taste good.
I'll give you indigestion.
A man. A tiny man.
You can't do this to me.
I've got a wife and kids.
Millions of kids.
Hold on there, mate.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Help! Put me down! Help! Help!
Drop that! Drop that!
Well, another one. Who are you?
Who me? What? I'm king around here.
Guards! Guards! To the turrets!
Archers! Surround the giant!
Surround the giant! Guards!
Well.
Huh! You'll pay for this.
Ready!
Aim, fire. Aim, fire.
Aim!
Fire, fire, fire.
How do you like that?
Want some more?
All right, let her go!
It's Bom
Bo!
Force the gates! Man the battlements!
Defend the city!
We're attacked! We're attacked!
Stop! Stop you swine!
Get back to your posts!
Get back there and fight!
We of Blefuscu are not!
... afraid of anything.
Well, where's everyone gone?
This is no way to treat a harmless visitor.
Look Gabby, we've won! Gabby! Gabby?
See Gabby? They've gone.
Yes, sir. Scared stiff.
Hello there.
Come now, don't let my size frighten you.
You, your majesty, surely
you're not afraid of me?
Nuh uh.
Well, good. Then let me present myself.
My name is Gulliver, your majesty.
Lemuel Gulliver, a shipwrecked sailor.
At your service.
Well, welcome to Lilliput,
Mr., Mr. Gulliver.
Uh Mr. Gulliver, can you fight?
Well your majesty,
I can lick anybody my size.
Ah, splendid, splendid!
I don't think Bombo will give us any
further trouble while you're around here.
No sir!
He's on our side, Gabby.
He's on our side!
There's nothing to fear!
The man mountain's on our side!
# All's well! What's a rainy day? #
# Never mind that cloud. #
# Behind that cloud you'll find a golden ray. #
# All's well! Laugh your fears away. #
# See the light ahead. Right ahead. #
# There's a moonlit night ahead. #
# Everyone, come on have fun. All's well! #
# All's well! All's well! All's well! #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay #
# For you and me for us and we #
# All the clouds have rolled away #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay #
# The sun shines bright and the world's all right #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay #
# For you and me for us and we #
# All the clouds have rolled away #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay #
# The sun shines bright and the world's all right #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Four and twenty sunbeams #
# Are dancing round my face #
# Four score and twenty more #
Come on, where are those buttons?
# Are dancing every place #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Toodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-oodle-lay #
# You can't go wrong if you sing that song #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day #
# Four and twenty sunbeams #
# Are dancing round my face #
# Four score and twenty more #
# Are dancing every place #
# You can't go wrong if you sing that song #
# It's a hap-hap-happy day! #
Out of soap! Push him up!
Outta the tub! He's a coming up!
Hey look out! Grab it! Pull it off! Nab it!
Pull it off! Take it off!
You understand that not until
that giant is removed
can our forces taste the sweet fruits of victory!
Now then, it is up to you to carry
this message to my spies in Lilliput.
Be off and may luck be with you!
Too-de-loo!
Get going!
Your majesty, I'm sorry the
little princess isn't with us.
Yes, too bad. Too much
excitement for one day.
Dear spies: Get rid of that Giant
or else... Cordially yours King Bombo
# There are bluebirds in the moonlight #
# Silly idea, bluebirds in the moonlight #
# But that's how I feel when I'm with you #
# There are night owls in the daylight #
# Silly idea, night owls in the daylight #
# Or maybe my heart is saying
whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo #
# Who is the one for us? #
# You - it's what you've done for us #
# There are bluebirds in the moonlight #
# Silly idea, bluebirds in the moonlight #
# But that's how I feel when I'm with you #
# There are bluebirds in the moonlight #
# Silly idea, bluebirds in the moonlight #
# But that's how I feel when I'm with you #
# There are night owls in the daylight #
# Silly idea, night owls in the daylight #
# I only think my heart is saying
whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo #
# Who is the one for us? #
# You - that's what you've done for us #
# There are bluebirds in the moonlight #
# Silly idea, bluebirds in the moonlight #
# But that's how I feel when I'm with you #
# I'm that way about you! #
Gulliver's thunder machine
# Come home again, come home #
# Wherever you may be #
# Come home again you sailor man, sailor man #
# Home again to the sea #
# I hear a dream all day #
# A dream that calls to me #
# Come home again you sailor man, sailor man #
# Home again to the sea #
Ahoy, mate! Ahoy, m...
Ahoy, mate! Ahoy! Ahoy!
I see that you're a sailor boy.
I owned a boat. A beauty, too.
Fifty times as big as your a,
as big as your a,
as big as your shoe.
My, my.
Hoy, hoy.
Lost her though in a glorious gale,
but I came home on
the back of a whale.
But tell me though how
you caught the whale.
Simply grabbed a hold of his tail.
My, my.
I, I,
I climbed a mountain peak so high.
I bumped my head against the sky.
And there I was, where was I?
On the Island of Alibi.
Hoy, hoy.
My, my.
Hi, hi.
But now my life is very dull.
They ought to make me an admiral.
Now that's the job that I'd enjoy.
I must be going. Ahoy! Ahoy!
My, my, my.
You put that ball in there.
And then it goes down and around.
Pull that thing.
And it comes out here.
The g-g-g-g-giant!
Wow!
The light. The light.
Douse the light!
He's gone.
Phew!
Hello! Anybody in there?
Nobody here but just us spi...
Chickens!
My, my.
# Forever, forever, #
# There won't be anyone but you. #
# Remember I'm true, my sweet. #
# Forever, forever, #
# La, la, la, la, la, la. #
Forever! Forever!
That's the song of Blefuscu!
A spy!
Charge!
A spy! A spy!
Where is he? Where did he go?
Concealing a spy.
And at a time of war, too.
That makes it worse!
Carry on the search men!
Mind you, your father will hear of this.
King Bombo,
Say the word and the giant is a dead duck.
..is a dead duck.
P.S. What do we do with the body?
Two hearts and a wedding
broken by a melody?
Incredible!
Wait a minute.
I have an idea that might turn
this malice to a melody!
Sing Faithful and Forever
together, as one song.
The giant will be a dead duck.
Ha! Now we are getting at somewhere!
Dear Spies, Destroy. Crush.
Obliterate! Annihilate!
Kill him!
I will attack at dawn!
Affectionately yours, Bombo.
Whatcha got there?
Attack at dawn. Attack..
Bombo's attack.., Bom..., Bom...
Guards! Guards! Guards!
Bombo's attacking! Bombo's attacking!
Bombo's attacking at dawn!
Bombo's attacking! It's war!
Bombo's attacking! It's war! It's war!
It's the end of the ending!
To the beach! To the beach!
Bomb.. attacking!
What?
Bombo attacking!
It's war! It's war!
To the beach! To the beach!
The enemy attacks!
To defend Lilliput.
To defend Lilliput!
Yes, forward march.
Gulliver! Gulliver! Where are you?
Bombo's attacking.
Where are you Gulliver?
We'll be wiped out!
Gulliver where are you?
Gulliver! Gulliver! Bombo's attacking!
It's war! Gulliver! It's war!
Gulliver! Where are you?
Gulliver! Gulliver! It's war!
Gulliver! Bombo's attacking!
Bombo's attacking! It's war!
Put me down.
Hah! Well, where you been you
lazy, long legged, overgrown lummox?
Now, get down there to that beach
and wipe out that Bombo
and that bunch of Blefuscuians.
And tear em to pieces
and don't leave a man alive
to tell the tale.
Forward march! Get going!
Aye, aye, sir!
My, oh my.
Hey! Wait for me.
Gulliver, wait for me!
Wait for me, Gulliver!
No note.
Where is it?
What did you done with it?
Where did you lose it?
Who's got it now?
Gulliver! Gulliver! Wait for me!
Gulliver! Gulliver!
Let me go! Let me go!
Let's go!
Hold on there!
We can settle this peacefully.
Listen!
Hold you fire!
Hear what I have to say.
Bombo, order your men
to lay down their arms.
Must I make you listen?
David, look! Gulliver's thunder machine.
Wait here, Glory.
David!
Fire!
Pull! Come on! Pull! Pull!
David!
Poor, poor, foolish little people.
Look what you've done.
Now go ahead! Break your nutshell heads
over your songs!
But did you have to break Glory's heart,
King Little,
because you are thoughtless and selfish?
And you Bombo, o mighty warrior,
what have you won?
You were too stubborn to think,
too busy quarrelling to lend ear to the
harmony that might have been yours.
But now in your sorrow and despair,
perhaps you will listen to your songs
as they might be sung.
# Faithful forever whatever I do #
# Remember I'm true, #
# remember that #
# Faithful forever and thankful for you #
# I'll keep smiling through, #
# remember that #
# We may be apart now and then #
# But I'll hold you in my heart #
# Till you're in my arms again #
# Faithful forever I promise to be #
# So always have faith in me #
In behalf of the peoples of
Blefuscu and Lilliput,
With eternal gratitude and love in our hearts,
we christen thee, Gulliver!
# Come back again, come back #
# Wherever you may be #
# Come back again you sailor man, sailor man #
# Back again from the sea #
-- The End --